[
    {
        "_id" : "1",
        "question" : "At 8 am, we received news that an old woman was murdered in a building. On reaching the crime scene, the watchman told us,\r\n“She was weird, once her husband asked which day it is, she said Thursday while it was Sunday. One day, after purchasing 4 apples she gave money to the seller for 8 apples. She left a note which reads \"LYWFERH\"\r\nWhat did she mean?”\r\n",
        "answer" : "husband",
        "hint" : "Old woman's disorder :  she counted any number  four more than the actual number ."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "2",
        "question" : "We thought her husband was the killer but he was blind and deaf and when frisked, another note was found in his pocket. It was clear until now that someone was playing with me.\r\nThe note now said  \r\n“In a mysterious case of sudden disappearance of Mr. Schlansky. A laptop is found in his office and needs to be accessed in order to get a clue about his whereabouts but it was password protected with a hint as follows:\r\n\r\nTake 4 pineapples and eat them with 4 toasts. If you don’t guess the password within the 3rd duck then, eat the 1st apricot kept to the side of 1st paper guarded by 4 tigers.\r\n\r\nFind the password.”\r\n",
        "answer" : "escape",
        "hint" : "Number is the position."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "3",
        "question" : "I noticed some footprints in the lawn, looked gigantic, but it was now clear by the leads that we had to escape.\r\nAs soon as we escaped, I received an SMS, it said:\r\n\r\n“Jorge Manley, a famous businessman was murdered. Yet no murderer was found. But the cops got witnesses. There were 5 other people in Jorge’s house. The Chef(Jack) said he was preparing breakfast. The Gardener(Jacob) said he was gardening. The Maid(Andrea) was outside cleaning the window as there was frost all over. The Wife(Lisbon) said she was watching TV. And then the grandfather(George) said he was in his wheelchair. Who murdered Jorge Manley(name)?”\r\n",
        "answer" : "Andrea",
        "hint" : "It was cold outside."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "4",
        "question" : "We started an immediate search for the maid (Andrea). We visited her house. We interrogated her husband, Carl about her whereabouts. The anxious husband told us that her wife hasn\u2019t been home since last night.\r\nOn searching the house, we found Carl's personal diary. Carl had a very abnormal handwriting which was difficult to understand.\r\nSuddenly we received a call from Hotel Caesars Palace and we were informed about a crime scene in their hotel. We reached the crime scene as soon as possible.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\u201CAndrea was found dead in her hotel room. Before the incident, she and her husband(Carl) were undergoing divorce. \r\n\r\nIn the room, all the fingerprints had been eliminated with ammonia. The label of the ammonia bottle used to clear the evidence was found which linked to the pharmaceutical company that Carl owned. \r\n\r\nThere was a handwritten note which said, \"She deserved this.\" The handwriting belonged to Carl, but looked like it was forged. \r\nA piece of torn cloth was found which turned out to be Carl's. This was an indication that there had been a struggle, however, there was no other evidence to support this cause. \r\n\r\nFurther investigation revealed that Carl suffered feats of aggression and also proved his dyslexia. \r\n\r\nAndrea was a troubled woman and had attempted suicide in the past. Carl used to lash out by beating her. The police concluded that this was a case of suicide.\r\nWhat piece of evidence gave it away?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "note",
        "hint" : "Carl is dyslexic."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "5",
        "question" : "We revisited Andrea’s house to gain more information about her. Carl went furious listening about what happened to Andrea. Later he disclosed that he came to know about Andrea’s and Jorge Manley’s affair. Carl sobbed and said,”I thought a couple of times to end Jorge Manley and Andrea but I decided to wait and see how long this goes”. Carl also stated that Andrea thought she was the only one Jorge Manley was involved with but later she found about his another affair and this might have forced Andrea to end this story right here.\r\nWe asked Carl whether he has any children?\r\nCarl said that he has a daughter named Olivia and is sleeping inside the bedroom.\r\nWe asked whether we could ask a few questions to her, to which she agreed.\r\nWhen he went inside to call Olivia, he screamed.\r\n\r\n“Carl’s 3 yrs old daughter Olivia, who was sleeping disappeared from the bedroom. In the bathroom, there was a glass in front of the mirror and a bathtub below it .They wrote on the glass that this may help to reach you to your daughter-  “call me at u3^373”. What was written on the glass?”\r\n",
        "answer" : "eleven",
        "hint" : "\u201CTo find Olivia one doesn\u2019t need help .\r\n      All must do is look to oneself\u201D\r\n"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "6",
        "question" : "There was no contact number listed so we just waited for that porcelain clock on the wall to proclaim the time as ELEVEN.\r\nWe received the call.\r\nA recorded audio was played…\r\n\r\n\r\nThe triangle ABC at the northern warehouse that has sides a=5, b=18.76, and c=15.398. Find angle C.\r\n\r\nAt the eastern warehouse there is the same question but find the angle A\r\n\r\nThey will lead you to the same place.\r\nFind the location?\r\n",
        "answer" : "Italy",
        "hint" : "The location is specified in degrees and directions ."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "7",
        "question" : "Italy! We were really amazed to see the power of the kidnapper to take Olivia overseas.\r\nWe assumed a great network involved. The only way to get Olivia was to visit Italy. \r\nAfter we went to Italy, while exiting from the airport, an officer said, “Welcome to Italy, Sherlock and John”, and gave us this letter:\r\n\r\n“Hello Sherlock and John. Actually, I don’t feel like giving the daughter right away. Solve this...\r\n‘A chemistry teacher was murdered soon after his last lecture, Wednesday evening.\r\nThe murderers left a note \"4.4.8.3.1.0.0.8\".\r\nBreak the code and find the names of two murderers’ ”\r\n",
        "answer" : "RuBi,NeO",
        "hint" : "It contains more than 100 things but it's not a jigsaw puzzle .\r\n    It is used in chemistry to check which thing is more stable .\r\n"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "8",
        "question" : "After we went to the chemistry Lab owned by RuBi and NeO, we found Olivia with a lead in her hand:\r\n\r\n\u201CI have 2 friends, Scarlett and Erin. Scarlett lies on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays. Whereas Erin lies on Mondays, Tuesdays, Thursdays, Saturdays, Sundays. \r\nToday they give the following statements.\r\nScarlett- I lie on Saturdays.\r\nErin- I will lie tomorrow\r\nScarlett- I'll lie on Sundays as well.\r\n\r\nWhich day is today?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "wednesday",
        "hint" : "Find an odd one out."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "9",
        "question" : "The next day was Wednesday.\r\nWe sensed something strange about this lead so we interrogated the daughter about the names.\r\nAs stated by the daughter those were her friends in London\r\nWe headed back to London to provide her friends security.\r\nBut we were then informed that Erin and Scarlett went on a trek trip with their friends.\r\n\r\n\u201CA group of 5 friends went on an adventure. They decided to climb a mountain.It was a winter evening, they started their journey in extreme cold. Two days later, when they were starting their climb for the day, they found Scarlett's body and she was poisoned. On investigating, Joe told that he was packing the bag. Hamid said he was the last to wake up. Erin told that he was cooking food for all and Winston said that he was mapping their route for the journey\r\nWho is most likely to be the killer?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "Erin",
        "hint" : "Winston said that the last time he saw scarlett was before breakfast."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "10",
        "question" : "We handed over Erin to the Police custody.\r\nWe knew it wasn\u2019t over but there were no new leads now.\r\n\r\nWe ran out of cash so we visited the nearby bank where we met most of the people I met on my wedding day. It seemed a bit fishy and until now everything meant to be so.\r\nHere the time arrived \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\u201CFour robbers Leo, Tommy, Harrison & Arlo planned to rob a bank. They entered the bank on a busy morning and sealed all entrances. One hostage was found dead. During the investigation Leo said he was breaking into the locker room. Arlo said he was looting all the cash from the cash desk. Harrison said he was guarding the entrances. Tommy said he was disabling the security cameras and alarms. Who killed the hostage?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "harrison",
        "hint" : "All the entrances were sealed"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "11",
        "question" : "Now the question is was this all planned or it was just a coincidence?\r\nWhy did Harrison do it?\r\nWhen interrogated he gave us a phone with a recorded audio\r\n\r\n\u201COkay Sherlock, welcome to the final round. That\u2019s enough of this game now. I feel like revealing my cards to you and my real name, but but but , let\u2019s play one last round.\r\n\r\nThere\u2019s a donkey murdered with a note on its tail. \r\nNote said \u201CHaha sherlock, you would need an eight legged table to solve that.\r\nTake this number you may need it, 150 165 142 145 162 164\u201D\r\nThe only way to get to the murderer is to solve the mystery note.\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "hubert",
        "hint" : "Donkey is the key."
    }
]